{
  "categories": [
    {
      "Mathematics": [
        {
          "Algebra": [
            {
              "question": "How much is the square root of 25?",
              "options": ["625", "5", "6", "7"],
              "answer": "5"
            },
            {
              "question": "How much is the square root of 169?",
              "options": ["14", "13", "9", "28561"],
              "answer": "13"
            },
            {
              "question": "The square root of 289 is?:",
              "options": ["17", "13", "21", "14"],
              "answer": "17"
            },
            {
              "question": "How much is 1 to the power of 0?",
              "options": ["1", "0", "0.5", "-1"],
              "answer": "1"
            },
            {
              "question": "How much is 3 to the power of 4?",
              "options": ["126", "81", "12", "412"],
              "answer": "81"
            },
            {
              "question": "How much is 4 to the power of 2?",
              "options": ["12", "8", "16", "32"],
              "answer": "16"
            },
            {
              "question": "What are the roots of the equation: x*x - 3 * 3 = 0?",
              "options": ["3 and -3", "1 and 0", "2 and 3", "no real roots"],
              "answer": "3 and -3"
            },
            {
              "question": "What are the roots of the equation: 4*x*x + x - 5 = 0?",
              "options": ["2 и 4", "-1 и 1.25", "2 и 6", "no real roots"],
              "answer": "3 и -3"
            },
            {
              "question": "What are the roots of the equation: 4*x*x + x + 3 + 8*x*x = 0?",
              "options": ["6 и -2", "-1 и 3", "-4 и 3", "no real roots"],
              "answer": "no real roots"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "Geometry": [
            {
              "question": "What is the formula to calculate the area of a circle?",
              "options": ["π*r*r", "π*π*r", "2*π*r", "4*r*r"],
              "answer": "π*r*r"
            },
            {
              "question": "What is the area of a circle with a 16cm diameter",
              "options": ["32π", "16π", "256π", "8π"],
              "answer": "32π"
            },
            {
              "question": "What is the area of a circle with a 6cm radius",
              "options": ["12π", "36π", "126π", "218π"],
              "answer": "36π"
            },
            {
              "question": "At least how many points do you need to form a plane?",
              "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
              "answer": "3"
            },
            {
              "question": "At least how many points do you need to form a segment?",
              "options": ["1", "4", "2", "3"],
              "answer": "2"
            },
            {
              "question": "How many points does a nonagon have?",
              "options": ["7", "3", "9", "6"],
              "answer": "9"
            },
            {
              "question": "A right-angled triangle ABC(C=90°) has coordinates of points A(2, 4) and B(6, 8).Find the coordinates of point C.",
              "options": ["C(6, 4)", "C(2, 6)", "C(4, 6)", "C(8, 2)"],
              "answer": "C(6, 4)"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "Stereometry":[
            {
              "question": "A sphere has a radius of 6cm. Find the volume of the sphere.",
              "options": ["288π", "864π", "144π", "432π"],
              "answer": "288π"
            },
            {
              "question":"A side of a cube is 4cm. How much is it's surface area?",
              "options": ["96", "64", "32", "16"],
              "answer":"96"
            },
            {
              "question": "A rectangular cuboid has sides a=12cm, b=7cm and c. If its volume is 1334 find c",
              "options": ["16cm", "32cm", "4cm", "11cm"],
              "answer": "16cm"
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "History": [
        {
          "Ancient History": [
            {
              "question": "Who is thought to be \"the father of history\"?",
              "options": ["Platon", "Aristotle", "Herodotus", "Socrates"],
              "answer": "Herodotus"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "Bulgarian History": [
            {
              "question": "What is the first bulgarian contitution called?",
              "options": ["The Revivalist Constitution", "The Plovdiv Constitution", "The Stanbolovian Constitution", "The Tarnovo Constitution"],
              "answer": "The Tarnovo Constitution"
            },
            {
              "question": "What year does bulgaria declare independece from the Ottoman empire?",
              "options": ["1787", "2023", "1878", "1867"],
              "answer": "1878"
            },
            {
              "question": "Under which ruler were the Bulgarians baptized??",
              "options": ["Boris I", "Peter I", "Simeon I", "Krum"],
              "answer": "Boris I"
            },
            {
              "question": "Unde which ruler Bulgaria had the largest territory in its history",
              "options": ["Boris I", "Peter I", "Simeon I", "Krum"],
              "answer":"Simeon I"
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "Geography": [
        {
          "Natural geography": [
            {
              "question": "Which nation the the island Bali belong to?",
              "options": ["Indonesia", "Malaysia", "New Zeland", "Australia"],
              "answer": "Indonesia"
            },
            {
              "question": "How much of the Earth is covered by water",
              "options": ["71%", "62%", "88%", "40.5%"],
              "answer": "71%"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "Geopolitics": [
            {
              "question": "Which is the largest country in the world?",
              "options": ["Canada", "USA", "India", "Russia"],
              "answer": "Russia"
            },
            {
              "question": "Inside which country is mount Everest located inside of?",
              "options": ["Nepal", "China", "Bhutan", "Pakistan"],
              "answer": "Nepal"
            },
            {
              "question": "Which city is the capital of Australia?",
              "options": ["Sidney", "Purt", "Canberra", "Melbourne"],
              "answer": "Canberra"
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
